<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA_no_include.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2022-12-20 at 10:53 p.m. --><mdRecord xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>uva-lib:2165650</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Virginia Law Review 1950-1951</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Holsinger's Studio (Charlottesville, Va.)</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>The Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>1950/1951</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Including members of the Class of 1951 and Class 0f 1952. Charles W. Berl, Jr., Martin V. Bostetter, Leonard Braman, Robert D. Bruce, Leroy T. Canoles, Jr., Joseph C. Carter, Jr., James E. Coleman, Jr., Stuart L Craig, Eldon H. Crowell, Endicott P. Davison, Robert E. L. DeButts, James L. Dooley, Robert Sears Dorsey, Robert Stanley Dorsey, Philip M. Drake, Albert W. Driver, Jr., Livingston Fairbank, Jr., Benjamin C. Flannagan, IV, Harvey W. Fort, Alan S. Gaynor, Marie S. Geddy, Vernon M. Geddy, Jr., Margaret E. Gordon, John D. Gray, David C. Green, Clarence F. Hicks, Edwin P. Hirsch, Decatur J. Holcombe, III, Jack P. Jefferies, Paul M. Lipkin, Pierce N. McCreary, L. Kent McElwain, Thomas V. Monahan, John H. Mudd, Oliver J. Neibel, Jr., Nelson T. Overton, Robert H. Patterson, Billups P. Percy, Alfred V. Prather, James W. Riddell, Raymond D. Saxe, Jr., Drayton T. Scott, Henry K. Skeele, George R. C. Stuart, Richard P. Taylor, Warren I. Titus, Jr., Charles A. Via, Jr., Richard E. Walck, Edward P. Webster, Joseph H. Young.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Original Negative Present [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The University of Virginia Visual History Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Faculty</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Students</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Charlottesville, Virginia, United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://iiif.lib.virginia.edu/iiif/uva-lib:2165650/full/!125,200/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://search.lib.virginia.edu/catalog/uva-lib:2165650</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>