<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA_no_include.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2022-12-20 at 10:52 p.m. --><mdRecord xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>uva-lib:2165495</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Law School Class of 1924</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Holsinger's Studio (Charlottesville, Va.)</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>The Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:description>Those pictured include: Edmund M. Wilson, Millard H. Patterson, Hawthorne D. Battle, Charles C. Carlin, Jr., John F. Galleher, William R. Seward, Herman L. Bennett, James R. V. Daniel, John S. Carroll, Collins Denny, Jr., Meredith E. Watkins, Edward H. Rowe, Jr., Bolling C. Stanley, Leslie D. Dawson, Garland R. Hubbard, Donald W. Shriver, Douglas A. Robertson, Nelson Fell, Orval R. Davis, John A. Richards, William Q. de Funiack, Richard D. Gilliam, Jr., Hugh S. Cumming, Jr., Littleton M. Wickham, Martin K. Fulk, William M. Neal, Hugh B. Marsh, Armstead M. Covington, Samuel A. Reinach, Jr., John T. Baxter, John A. Slagen, Lucien M. Abbot, Marshall T. Bohannon, Alpheus W. Embry, Frank Talbott, Jr., Theodore J. Amelson, Manley P. Caldwell, William V. Frazier, Jr., Charles S. Valentine, William S. D. Woods, Richard R. Florance, Jr., Charles E. A. Knight, Stoner M. Scott, Charles N. Hulvey, Samuel R. Cheek Jr. Also pictured: School of Law faculty members George B. Eager, Jr., William H. Lile, Dean Ribble, Charles A. Graves.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Original Negative Present [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The University of Virginia Visual History Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Faculty</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Students</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Charlottesville, Virginia, United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://iiif.lib.virginia.edu/iiif/uva-lib:2165495/full/!125,200/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://search.lib.virginia.edu/catalog/uva-lib:2165495</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>