<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd"
      type="application/xml"
      schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2023-06-13 at 2:38 p.m. -->
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>1783410</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Pennsylvania Station, exterior|general view</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:title>Baltimore Union Station</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:title>Penn Station</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Murchison, Kenneth M. (American architect, 1872-1938) [work]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Wilson, Richard Guy [photographer]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>1986</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Signal tower</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Pennsylvania Station (generally referred to as Penn Station) is the main train station in Baltimore, Maryland. Designed by New York architect Kenneth MacKenzie Murchison (1872–1938), it was constructed in 1911 in the Beaux-Arts style of architecture for the Pennsylvania Railroad. It is located at 1515 N. Charles Street, on a raised "island" of sorts between two open trenches, one for the Jones Falls Expressway and the other the tracks of the Northeast Corridor. The Mount Vernon neighborhood lies to the south, and Station North is to the north. Penn Station is about a mile and a half north of downtown and the Inner Harbor. The station was originally known as Union Station (because it was served by both Pennsylvania Railroad and Western Maryland Railway), but was renamed to match other Pennsylvania Stations in 1928. Both the northern and southern Northeast Corridor (NEC) approaches into the station are tunneled. The two-track Baltimore and Potomac Tunnel (B&amp;P Tunnel), which opened in 1873, constitutes the southern approach. At 7,660 feet (about 1.5 miles) in length, it is one of the worst bottlenecks on the NEC since the maximum speeds for trains through the tunnel is only 30 mph. The northern approach for Penn Station is carried through the Union Tunnel, which has a single-track bore and a double-track bore. The Union Tunnel was opened in 1873 and has been upgraded since, and is not as bad a chokepoint as the B&amp;P tunnel, since it has two bores and lacks the sharp curves and steep grades that its opposite to the south has. Penn Station is the eighth busiest rail station in the United States by number of passengers served. -- http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baltimore_Union_Station [work]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>American</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Beaux-Arts</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>Richard Guy Wilson Archive</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>Architecture and City Planning</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Pennsylvania Railroad</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Western Maryland Railroad Company</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Amtrak</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>railroad signal towers</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>roofing tile</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>bay windows</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>1515 North Charles Street, Baltimore, Baltimore Independent City, Maryland, United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:spatial>39.3074, -76.6156</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://stor.artstor.org/iiif/2013/08/07/12/1375ee74-77f8-423c-9b95-8b28343fd73e_deflate.tif/full/!250,250/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>https://search.lib.virginia.edu/items/i_1783410</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
