<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd"
      type="application/xml"
      schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2022-06-17 at 3:32 p.m. -->
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>675655</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Calvary Church, exterior</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Renwick, James (American architect, 1818-1895) [work]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Wilson, Richard Guy [photographer]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>[1842..1848]</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>General view</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Calvary Church is an Episcopal church located at 273 Park Avenue South on the corner of East 21st Street in the Gramercy Park neighborhood of Manhattan, New York City, on the border of the Flatiron District. It was designed by James Renwick, Jr., the architect who designed St. Patrick's Cathedral and Grace Church, and was completed in 1848. The church complex is located within the Gramercy Park Historic District and Extension.The Calvary Church parish was founded in 1832, and initially used a wooden-frame church on what was then Fourth Avenue – which has since become Park Avenue – uptown of its current site. That building was moved to the current location in 1842, and the new Renwick-designed Gothic Revival sanctuary was completed in 1848. Renwick patterned Calvary after twin-towered French cathedrals, but, unlike Grace Church, Calvary was constructed of brownstone. The church's two wooden spires were removed in the early 20th century because of deterioration. The church complex also includes the nine-story Calvary House, east of the church on Gramercy Park North (East 21st Street), also designed by Renwick, and built in 1867, and the "Renwick Gem" Schoolhouse, a small building to the north of the church which was built as a theatre but used for that purpose only for a short time before being utilized for the Calvary Church Sunday school. It has a large interior space, about 27 feet between the columns, which were designed to hold up the heavy slate roof without the use of exterior buttresses. The building, which as of 2011 houses the 4th and 5th grade classes of the École Internationale de New York, compensates for the shadowing of the taller buildings around through Renwick's use of 42 clerestory windows. It is one of the two sanctuaries of the Calvary-St. George's Parish. http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Calvary_Church_(Manhattan) [work]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>American</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Gothic Revival</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>Richard Guy Wilson Archive</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>Architecture and City Planning</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>religious buildings</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Episcopal</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>façades</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>gables (architectural elements)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>pointed arches</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>rose windows</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>running ornament</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>stained glass (visual works)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>273 Park Avenue South, New York, United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:spatial>40.739091, -73.987091</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://stor.artstor.org/iiif/2012/08/02/15/6987c47e-ba89-44d2-8fe5-50c401eef490_deflate.tif/full/!250,250/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>https://search.lib.virginia.edu/items/i_675655</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
