<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA_no_include.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2021-11-23 at 8:41 a.m. --><mdRecord xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>uva-lib:2524251</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Homeopathic medicine set</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Dr. Arthur Lutze [manufacturer]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>The Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>1875~</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:extent>6 x 13 x 22.2 cm [original]</dcterms:extent>
   <dcterms:medium>glass (material); wood and wood products; paper (fiber product); corks (stoppers) [original]</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:description>Wooden case labeled "144 Homoopathische Potenzen vom Sanitatsrath Dr. Arthur Lutze in Coethen." 144 vials include: Aconit, Agaricus muse, Agnus cast, Alumina, Aluminium met, Ambra, Ammonium carb, Anacardium, Angustura, Apis, Antimon crud, Argentum fol, Argent nitric, Arnica, Arsenicum, Asa foetida, Asarum europ, Aurum fol, Baryta carb, Belladonna, Benzoes acid, Borax, Brom, Bovista, Bryonia, Cahinca, Calcar carb, Calcar caust, Calcar phosph, Calendula, camphora, Cannabis sat, Cancer fluviat, Cantharides, Capsicum, Carbo animalis, Carbo vegetab, Causticum, Cepa, Chamaedris, Chamomilla, China, Chlor, Cicuta, Cina, Cistus canad, Clematis erecta, Cocculus, Coccus cacti, Coffea, Colchicum, Colocynthis, Conium, Crocus, Crotalus, Cuprum, Daphne indica, Digitalis, Drosera, Dulcamara, Euphorbium, Euphrasia, Ferrum, Glonoin, Graphit, Hellebor niger, Hepar sulph, Hydrocyani ac, Hyoscyamus, Hypericum, Iatropha cure, Ignatia, Jod, Ipecacuanha, Kali bichrom, Kali carb, Kreosot, Lachsesis, Laurocerasus, Ledum palustre, Lycopodium, Magnesia carb, Magnesia mur, Mancinella, Manganum, Menyanthes, Mephitis putor, Mercur, Mezereum, Millefollium, Moschus, Muriatis acid, Natrum carbon, Natrum muriat, Nitri acidum, Nitrum, Nux moschata, Nux vomica, Oleander, Opium, Petroleum, Phosphori ac, Phosphorus, Platina, Plumbum, Psoricum, Pulsatilla, Pyrocarbon, Ranunc bulb, Ranunc sceler, Rheum, Rhododendron, Rhus toxicod, Ruta, Sabadilla, Sabina, Sambucus nig, Singuinaria, Secale cornut, Selenium, Senega, Sepia, Silicea, Spigelia, Spirit sulph 1, Spongia, Squilla, Stannum, Staphysagria, Stramonium, Sulphur, Sulphuris acid, Symphytum, Tartarus emet, Terebinthina, Teucrium mar, Thuja, Urtica urens, valeriana, Variolin, Veratrum alb, Vinca minor, Viola tric, Zincum metall.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Photographed by Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, Historical Collections and Services staff.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The University of Virginia Medical Artifacts Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC-NC/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>Pharmacy--supplies--Homeopathic pharmacy</dcterms:subject>
   <edm:preview>https://iiif.lib.virginia.edu/iiif/uva-lib:2524251/full/!125,200/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://search.lib.virginia.edu/catalog/uva-lib:2524251</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>