<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA_no_include.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2021-11-23 at 5:40 a.m. --><mdRecord xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>uva-lib:1825245</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Tales / by Edgar A. Poe. The raven and other poems / Edgar A. Poe</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:title>Poe's tales. The raven and other poems</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>McGregor Fund.</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Poe, Edgar Allan, 1809-1849</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Smith, Thomas B., active 19th century</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Tracy W. McGregor Library. American History Collection.</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Wiley &amp; Putnam</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>Wiley and Putnam, 161 Broadway</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>1845</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:extent>[6], 228, [8], 91, [9] p.</dcterms:extent>
   <dcterms:extent>20 cm [original]</dcterms:extent>
   <dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language>
   <dcterms:description>Tales: The gold-bug -- The black cat -- Mesmeric revelation -- Lionizing -- The fall of the house of Usher -- A descent into the maelström -- The colloquy of Monos and Una -- The conversation of Eiros and Charmion -- The murders in the Rue Morgue -- The mystery of Marie Roget -- The purloined letter -- The man in the crowd -- The raven and other poems: The raven -- The valley of unrest -- Bridal ballad -- The sleeper -- The Coliseum -- Lenore -- Catholic hymn -- Israfel -- Dream-land -- Sonnet--to Zante -- The city in the sea -- To one in Paradise -- Eulalie, a song -- To F__s S. O__d -- To F__ -- Sonnet -- Silence -- The conqueror worm -- The haunted palace -- Scenes from "Politan" -- Poems written in youth: Sonnet--to science -- Al Aaraaf -- Tamerlane -- A dream -- Romance -- Fairy-land -- To __ -- To the river -- -- The lake --To __ -- Song -- To Helen.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Copyright page (p. [4]) in Poe's Tales: "Entered according to Act of Congress, in the year 1845, by Wiley &amp; Putnam, in the Clerk's Office of the District Court for the Southern District of New-York."</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>"Sheets of the second and third printings issued bound together with Poe's The Raven and other Poems, 1845. ... Copies occur with either Tales or The Raven bound first." See BAL.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>"T.B. Smith, Stereotyper, 216 William Street." -- on verso of title page for The Raven.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Signatures: [1]⁴ 2-15⁸ 16²; ²[1]⁴ [2-3]⁸ 4⁸ chi⁸ 5⁸ 7⁸ [8]².</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>"Poems written in youth" (p. [53]-91) in The Raven has foot-note "Private reasons -- some of which have reference to the sin of plagiarism, and others to the date of Tennyson's first poems -- have induced me, after some hesitation, to re-publish these, the crude compositions of my earliest boyhood. They are printed verbatim -- without alteration from the original edition -- the date of which is too remote to be judiciously acknowledged. E.A.P." (though not reprinted exactly "verbatim", the changes were unimportant)--cf. George E. Woodberry, Life of Poe, v. 2 (1909), p. 163; also John W. Robertson, Edgar A. Poe, 1921, p. 332-334.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Publisher's advertisement (8 p.) bound at the end of The Raven: "New and valuable books published by Wiley and Putnam, 161 Broadway, N.Y."</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>SPECIAL COLLECTIONS: Original blind stamped brown cloth binding with patterned endpapers. Signature of Louise D. Nowell on half title and front endpaper. Newspaper clipping pasted inside front cover. Tracy W. McGregor Library, American History Collection. This copy recataloged through a generous grant from the McGregor Fund.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>Wiley and Putnam's library of American books</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>Detective and mystery stories</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Horror tales, American</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>New York (City), New York (State), United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://iiif.lib.virginia.edu/iiif/uva-lib:305678/full/!125,200/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://search.lib.virginia.edu/catalog/uva-lib:1825245</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>