<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd"
      type="application/xml"
      schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2023-06-13 at 2:41 p.m. -->
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>2058194</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Musée du Louvre, general view</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:title>Louvre Museum</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:title>Louvre Palace</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:title>Palais du Louvre</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Wilson, Richard Guy [photographer]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>[1190..1991]</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Cour Napoleon, showing Pavillon Turgot and Pavillon Richelieu</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>The museum is housed in the Louvre Palace, originally built as a fortress in the late 12th century under Philip II. Remnants of the fortress are visible in the basement of the museum. The building was extended many times to form the present Louvre Palace; In the 14th century, Charles V converted the building into a residence and in 1546, Francis I began the renovation of the site in French Renaissance style. In 1682, Louis XIV chose the Palace of Versailles for his household, leaving the Louvre primarily as a place to display the royal collection. By the mid-18th century there was an increasing number of proposals to create a public gallery, and during the French Revolution, the National Assembly decreed that the Louvre should be used as a museum to display the nation's masterpieces. [work]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>By 1874, the Louvre Palace had achieved its present form of an almost rectangular structure with the Sully Wing to the east containing the square Cour Carrée and the oldest parts of the Louvre; and two wings which wrap the Cour Napoléon, the Richelieu Wing to the north and the Denon Wing, which borders the Seine to the south. In 1983, French President François Mitterrand proposed ... the Grand Louvre plan to renovate the building and relocate the Finance Ministry, allowing displays throughout the building. Architect I. M. Pei was awarded the project and proposed a glass pyramid to stand over a new entrance in the main court, the Cour Napoléon. The pyramid and its underground lobby were inaugurated on 15 October 1988; the pyramid was completed in 1989. The second phase of the Grand Louvre plan, La Pyramide Inversée (The Inverted Pyramid), was completed in 1993. [work]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>French</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>Richard Guy Wilson Archive</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>Architecture and City Planning</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>art museums</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>national museums</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>royal palaces</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>adaptive reuse</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>courtyards</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>pavilions (building divisions)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>gardens</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Paris, Ville de Paris, Département de, Île-de-France, France</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:spatial>48.8667, 2.3333</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://stor.artstor.org/iiif/2022/07/28/13/67876849-c5fd-4000-93e2-a61758c05903_deflate.tif/full/!250,250/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>https://search.lib.virginia.edu/items/i_2058194</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
