<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA_no_include.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2022-12-20 at 11:07 p.m. --><mdRecord xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>uva-lib:2168535</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Second Year Class, 1926-1927</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Holsinger's Studio (Charlottesville, Va.)</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>The Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>1926/1927</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>SOM, Class of 1929 Students unidentifed. Student roster in alphabetical order, not as appears in photos. Walter J. Allegree, Thomas L. Allman, Dewey L. Anderson, James P. Baker Jr., Wilbur A. Barker, John W. Bolen, Thomas Bradley, Francis L. Byers, Aubrey R. Carter, Hower R. Coleman Jr., Carl C. Cooley, Frank D. Costenbader, John M. C. Covington, Belle B. Dale, Alva D. Daughton, John R. Eggleston, Muarice M. Fliess, Hagop Gasparian, Arthur E. Glover, John M. Green, John H. Greene, Charles S. Groseclose, Eugene S. Groseclose, Donald O. Hamblin, Tarring W. Heironimus Jr., Guy W. Horsley, William C. Hutcheson, Troy H. Hutchinson, Jed J. Irvine, Eric F. Joslin, Charles Kavovit, Thomas C. Lawford, Maurice L. LeBauer, Sidney F. LeBauer, Meyer H. Legum, Archibald A. Little, Henry W. Litvack, Robert B. Lobban, Jules R. London, James L. Long, Robert W.C. McClanahan, Paul R. McFadyen, Alexander T. Mayo, Jose Menedez, Alberto Navaroo, Paul Otto, Minor B. Payne, Robert T. Peirce Jr., Robert E. Peyton, Frederick Pilcher Jr., John A. Pilcher Jr., Charles L. Savage, Lillie S. Shenk, Joseph M. Sloan, William C. Stephenson Jr., Christopher M. Turman Jr., Oliver L. Von Canon, John D. D. Ware, Hyman B. Weinberg, Harrison R. Wesson, Julius E. West, Isaac H. White, William L. Williams, Herbert D. Wolff, Jr., Bascom B. Young,</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Original Negative Present [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The University of Virginia Visual History Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Faculty</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Students</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Charlottesville, Virginia, United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://iiif.lib.virginia.edu/iiif/uva-lib:2168535/full/!125,200/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://search.lib.virginia.edu/catalog/uva-lib:2168535</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>