<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA_no_include.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2022-06-20 at 10:00 a.m. --><mdRecord xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>uva-lib:2168847</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Hospital House Staff, 1962-1963</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:publisher>The Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>1962/1963</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>First row (l to r): William H. Admirand, Ralph J. Alfidi, Joel W. Allgood, Burness F. Ansell, Jr., Joseph E. Anderson, Jr., L. Davis Arbuckle, Jr., A. W. Auld, Carlos R. Ayers, Dwight C. Babcock. Second row (l to r): Burton I. Benjamin, Lawrence A. Bernert, Jr., J. Michael Bestler, John P. Blackburn, Richard E. Boden, Gray T. Boyette, Mark E. Bradley, H. Dale Brown, James R. Brunk. Third row (l to r): Richard F. Bunting, William F. Burnett, Ronald H. Butcher, Joseph C. Campbell, Donald Caton, William M. Chadduck, Lee A. Clark, Jr., Richard E. Clark, Charles H. Colvin, III. Fourth row (l to r): F. Ellison Conrad, Robert T. Corney, Junius E. Crowgey, William J. Crowley, Robert Cserr, Charles W. Cummings, Joseph H. Cutchin, Jr., Edward K. Davis, M. R. Cooper. Fifth row (l to r): Cosmo A. Di Fazio, Jon D. Dorman, Mitchell J. Dreese, Charles L. Echols, Jr., Winston S. Ekren, William W. Ellis, William N. Evans, Alexander V. Fakadej. Sixth row (l to r): Bruce L. Fariss, P. R. Fazzone, Joseph G. Fiveash, Jr., Robert H. Fleming, J. T. Foster, J. Sidney Fulmer, Eduardo Garcia, James A. Gardner, Wallace K, Garner. Seventh row (l to r): Clifford L. Garrard, Jr., Glen E. Garrison, William P. Gibbs, Fred M. Gold, Jose A. Gomez, William H. Grey, W. B. Grine, John A. Habra. Eighth row (l to r): Robert P. Hadley, F. J. Hague, Peter Hairston, Robert B. Hall, Winthrop H. Hall, George H. Hansen, Russell E. Herring, Jr., C. M. Herbert, Jr. Ninth row (l to r): David T. Hochberg, J. Hayden Hollingsworth, John E. Hoopes, Richard S. Howard, A. N. Hremos, James G. Hunter, Jr., Michael B. Hussey, Troy H. Hutchinson, III, P. Hampton Hylton, Jr. Tenth row (l to r): Bulent Jajuli, Robert H. Jennings, Paul W. Johenning, James A. Johnson, Richard F. Jones, III, James G. Kavanaugh, Jr., John B. Kayan, Douglas E. Kennemore, Donald J. Kenneweg.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Original Negative Present [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The University of Virginia Visual History Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Faculty</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Students</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Charlottesville, Virginia, United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://iiif.lib.virginia.edu/iiif/uva-lib:2168847/full/!125,200/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://search.lib.virginia.edu/catalog/uva-lib:2168847</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>