<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd"
      type="application/xml"
      schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA_no_include.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2023-06-23 at 9:50 a.m. --><mdRecord xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>uva-lib:2168641</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>School of Medicine, Third Year Class, 1948-1949</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Holsinger's Studio (Charlottesville, Va.)</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>The Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>1948/1949</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>First row (l to r): Charles Old Barclay, Jr., William Russell Brooks, George Allen Buckmaster, Robert Sims Caldwell, James Campbell Cantrill, Floyd Wilson Carneal, Jr., John Baldwin Catlett, James Colvin Causey, John Archibald Campbell Colston, Jr., Paul Tulane Craddock, Fred Seldon Cruser. Second row (l to r): James Andrew DeLozier, Harrison Fertig, Robert Jerold Frank, Claude Robertson Garfield, William Buhrman Garland, Jr., Lawrence Noah Gilliam, Warren Collins Gregory, Thomas Marion Hall, Rozelle Hahn, Reginald Buchanan Henry, Jr., George William Herring. Third row (l to r): Seth Guilford Hobart, Guy Foster Hollifield, James Morrison Hutcheson, Jr., Patricia Ann Lawrence, Theodore Lather Marks, Paul Randall Marsh, Marion Dees Miller, Samuel Edmund Miller, Robert Edgar Mitchell, Jr. Fourth row (l to r): Beryl Macy Oser, Gladys Pietri-Oms Sutherland, Rupert Wilson Quaintance, Jr., Richard Eugene Rankin, Josiah Frederick Reed, Jr., James Cipriano Respess, Dorothy Louella Reycroft, Benjamin Price Riley, Jr., John Kenneth Robertson, William Henry Romm. Fifth row (l to r): Robert Louis Rowan, Roy Preston Sandidge, Jr., Edward Akira Sawada, Joseph Leon Schwartz, Jr., Jose Anibal Semidey, Elmer Oswald Smith, Jr., Russell Smith, David Valentine Strider, Frank Eugene Taylor, Bruce Edward Toppin, Clarence Brock Trower, Jr. Sixth row (l to r): Glenn Brady Updike, Jr., Charles William Wagner, James Mounts Wolcott, Jr., James Burnley Wood, William Geoffrey Wysor, Jr.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Original Negative Present [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The University of Virginia Visual History Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Faculty</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Students</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Charlottesville, Virginia, United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://iiif.lib.virginia.edu/iiif/uva-lib:2168641/full/!125,200/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://search.lib.virginia.edu/catalog/uva-lib:2168641</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>