<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd" type="application/xml"
      schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA_no_include.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2024-06-19 at 8:16 a.m. --><mdRecord xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>uva-lib:2168547</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>School of Medicine, Second Year Class, 1930-1931</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Holsinger's Studio (Charlottesville, Va.) [photographer]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:created>1930/1931</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Class of 1933 Identified (L to R): First row: Charles Jefferson Albright, Charles Varner Amole, Edwin Edmunds Barksdale, Nathaniel Lewis Bosworth, Jr., Hugh Roland Butt, William Bernard Carpenter, Charles Henry Conley, Jr., Cesare Frances DeBiase, John Essary Dees, Clayton Bernard Ethridge, Glassell Slaughter Fitz-Hugh, Harrison Fitzgerald Flippin, Edgar Coley Garrard, William Grossman, Jr. Second row: Henry Hamilton Hammer, Wallace Edgar Herrell, Joseph Martin Hitch, Jr., John Bohannan Hozier, Jr., Jethro Meriwether Hurt, Frederick Matthews Jacobs, William Roy Johnson, Colman Carnegie Johnston, Robert Archer Goodwin Jones, Walter LeRoy Kilby, Edward Linden Kinney, Gershon John Levin, Eleanor Holman McCoy, Hulburt Christopher McCoy Third row: Lewis Walke McIlhany, Edgar Prentice McKinney, Roger Gregory Magruder, Charles Hampton Mauzy, Jr., Thomas Andrew Moneymaker, Harold George Nix, Isaac Nathan Patterson, Asher Richardson Payne, Frederick Ralph Person, Jack Berry Porterfield, Charles Walton Purcell, William Alexander Read Fourth row: Charles Wolfe Rieber, William Randolph Robins, Jr., John Adrian Sims, John Thompson Brown Strode, John A. Moorman Thompson, George Nathaniel Thrift, John Watkins Trenis, Robert Irvine Trent, Randolph Beaton Turnbull, Algernon Keeling Turner, Vernon Atwill Turner, Wat Henry Tyler Fifth row: Ernest Thomas Upson, John Ernest Vaughan, George Edward Waters, Herman Weinberg, Robert William White, Jr., William Hoge Wood, Jr. [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Original Negative Present [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Faculty</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Students</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Charlottesville, Virginia, United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://iiif.lib.virginia.edu/iiif/uva-lib:2168547/full/!125,200/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>https://search.lib.virginia.edu/sources/uva_library/items/uva-lib:2168547</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>