<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA_no_include.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2022-06-20 at 9:59 a.m. --><mdRecord xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>uva-lib:2168533</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Second Year Class, 1925-1926</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Holsinger's Studio (Charlottesville, Va.)</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>The Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>1925/1926</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>SOM, Class of 1928 Students unidentified. Student roster in alphabetical order, not as appears in photo: James R. Adams, Walter J. Allegree, Joe W. Baker, Rufus Brittain, Clavin T. Burton, Arthur P. Butt Jr., John A. Calhoun Jr., Paul D. Camp Jr., Alexander N. Chaffin, Elizabeth C. Cole, John H. Coulter Jr., Alva D. Daughton, Albert M. Eaddy, Louis H. Edmunds, Daniel Fallis, Carson L. Fifer, Truman E. Gilbert, Joseph B. Graham, Loren P. Guy, Edward B. Holmes, Hubert B. Holsinger, William R. Jordan, Eric F. Joslin, Charles A. Kelly, Virgin L. Kelly Jr., Robert L. King, Walter J. Lackey, William L. Lacy, Max Landman, Ford K. Lucas, Paul R. MacFadyen Jr., Paul McFarlane, John B. McKee, Vincent G. Maggiore, Vincent J. Meads, Rufus F. Morgan, Oscar N. Morison, Cecil E. Newell, Chester R. Nuckolls, Irving Perlman, David S. Phlegar Jr., Frank C. Pinkerton, Valentine L. Puig Jr., Milton E. Robbins, Herman D. G. Rose, Harry J. Secky, Morris H. Spindel, Charles B. Stringfellow, Morris G. Strulowitz, Frank E. Tappan, Rudolph C. Thomason, Frank F. Thweatt Jr., Emory E. Walter, Charles E. Watson, James W. Watts II, Albert M. Wheeler, William A. Wiley, Jacob Wilkins, John F. Woodward Jr., Patrick T. Wu, Max Yacht</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Original Negative Present [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>The University of Virginia Visual History Collection</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Faculty</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Students</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Charlottesville, Virginia, United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://iiif.lib.virginia.edu/iiif/uva-lib:2168533/full/!125,200/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>http://search.lib.virginia.edu/catalog/uva-lib:2168533</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>