<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd" type="application/xml"
      schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA_no_include.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2024-06-19 at 8:16 a.m. --><mdRecord xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>uva-lib:2168639</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>School of Medicine, First Year Class, 1946-1947</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Holsinger's Studio (Charlottesville, Va.) [photographer]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:created>1946/1947</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Front row (l to r): Charles Old Barclay, Jr., Herbert Julian Bolin, Jr., William Russell Brooks, Defoix F. Caldwell, James Campbell Cantrill, Floyd Woodson Carneal, James Calvin Causey, John Archibald Campbell Colston, Jr., Paul Tulane Craddock, Fred Seldon Cruser, John Caulfield Dalton. Second row (l to r): Leonid Ebin, Kenneth Hall Epple, William Nichol Eskridge, Harrison Fertig, Robert Jerold Frank, Claude Robertson Garfield, Walter Buhrman Garland, Jr., Lawrence Noah Gilliam, John Gravatt Goodwin. Third row (l to r): Warren Collins Gregory, Thomas Marion Hall, Reginald Buchanan Henry, Guy Foster Hollifield, James Morrison Hutcheson, Jr., Charles William Jennings, Molly Jane Kirk, Joseph Talmadge Kirkland, Patricia Ann Lawrence, John Edward Loyd, Jr. Fourth row (l to r): Theodore Lathers Marks, Paul Randall Marsh, Edward Joseph mears, Marion Dees Miller, Samuel Edmund Miller, Robert Edgar Mitchell, Robert Frances Mitchell, Beryl Macy Oser, Rupert Wilson Quaintance, Jr., Josiah Frederick Reed, Jr., James Cipriano Respess, Dorothy Luella Reycroft. Fifth row (l to r): Benjamin Price Riley, Jr., William Henry Romm, Robert Louis Rowan, Joseph Leon Schwartz, Jr., Finley Larew Shields, Craig Neelands Smith, Elmer Oswald Smith, Jr., Russell Smith, David Valentine Strider, Bruce Edward Toppin, Clarence Brock Trower, Jr. Sixth row (l to r): Glenn Brady Updike, Jr., Charles William Wagner, Moffet Robson Walker, Charles Sharpe Willcox, James Mounts Wolcott, Jr., James Burnley Wood, Paul Howard Wornom, William Geoffrey Wysor, Jr. [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Original Negative Present [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Faculty</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>University of Virginia--Students</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Charlottesville, Virginia, United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://iiif.lib.virginia.edu/iiif/uva-lib:2168639/full/!125,200/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>https://search.lib.virginia.edu/sources/uva_library/items/uva-lib:2168639</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>