<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd" type="application/xml"
      schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA_no_include.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2024-06-19 at 11:03 a.m. --><mdRecord xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>text</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>uva-lib:838343</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>The Early Italian poets from Ciullo d'Alcamo to Dante Alighieri (1100-1200-1300): in the original metres : together with Dante's Vita nuova / translated by D.G. Rossetti</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:contributor>Chiswick Press. [original]</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:contributor>Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882 [original]</dcterms:contributor>
   <dcterms:created>1861</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:extent>xxxvi, 451 p. ; 19 cm.</dcterms:extent>
   <dcterms:description>pt. I. Poets chiefly before Dante -- pt. II Dante and his circle.</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>One of at least 6 proof copies, described by Rossetti in an undated letter to William Allingham: "I am sending you by book post with this a sewed copy of my book. I have only just got a few, and do not offer it to you en permanence in this state, as I am going to make an etching, or perhaps two, for it, and there is another index to come at the end, but had 6 copies sent me now to use in getting a publisher, etc." Cf. Fredeman article described below. [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>For an in-depth discussion of the history of the publication of "Early Italian poets," see the article by William E. Fredeman, in Bibliographical notes &amp; queries, Book Collector, v. 10, 1961, p. 193-198. Another article by Charles Cox and Simon Nowell-Smith, identifying even more cancelled leaves, appeared in Book Collector, v. 25, no. 4, Winter, 1976, p. 547-548. [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>This copy has the uncancelled leaves E6 (p. 59-60), F2 (p. 67-68) and H4 (p. 103-4) and cancellans for B2 (p. 3-4), B6 (p. 11-12), and H1 (p. 97-8) bound in. It is accompanied by a separate packet containing half-title and the new un-illustrated title page with Smith, Elder &amp; Co. imprint, cancellans for leaves E6, F2 and H4, and a reissue of the last gathering GG (p. 449-464) which includes index, with printer's imprint moved from p. 451 to 464. Inscribed on half-title "To Harry Ward Esq. with friendly regards. D.G. Rossetti. Xmas /61." [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Issued in 1874, in rearranged form, under title: Dante and his circle. [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>"List of the works which have chiefly contributed to the materials of the present volume": p. xi-xii. [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>SPECIAL COLLECTIONS: Errata pencilled inside back cover. Contemporary morocco; spine detached. In blue morocco clamshell box. Copies of the cited articles are laid in box. Robert and Virginia Tunstall Trust Fund and Robert Tunstall Fund, 2004/2005. [original]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>Italian poetry--Translations into English</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Italian poetry--To 1400</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:temporal>To 1400</dcterms:temporal>
   <edm:preview>https://iiif.lib.virginia.edu/iiif/uva-lib:1052687/full/!125,200/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>https://search.lib.virginia.edu/sources/uva_library/items/u4241670</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>