<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd"
      type="application/xml"
      schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2022-12-14 at 8:15 p.m. -->
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>3021588</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Station Square, general view</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Atterbury, Grosvenor (American architect, 1869-1956) [work]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Olmsted, Frederick Law, Jr. (American landscape architect, 1870-1957) [work]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Wilson, Richard Guy [photographer]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>1981</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:description>Plaza</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Forest Hills Gardens is a planned community located in Forest Hills, in the New York City borough of Queens. Its streets are privately owned but open to traffic. The area consists of a 142-acre (0.57 km2) development, fashioned after a traditional English village, that is one of America's oldest planned communities. It is modeled after the English planned garden suburb community Hampstead Garden Suburb, located near Golders Green, in London. The layout, with a central "square", and the similarity of many of the street names in both communities was clearly intentional. The community, founded in 1908, consists of about 800 homes, townhouses, and apartment buildings, mostly in Tudor, Brick Tudor or Georgian style, in a parklike setting designed by Frederick Law Olmsted, Jr. Designed with transportation access in mind, the community's central square is adjacent to the Forest Hills Long Island Rail Road station. -- http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Forest_Hills_Gardens,_Queens Grosvenor Atterbury renowned architect was given the commission to design the Forest Hills Gardens. Atterbury designed elegant, substantial Tudor and Colonial style homes. Throughout the Gardens you will see towers, spires, fancy brickwork. http://www.foresthillschamber.org/en/history/ The gateway to Forest Hills Gardens is Station Square, a brick-paved plaza dominated by the tower of the Forest Hills Inn, bordered on one side by the embankment of the railroad station and on the other by a continuously arcaded building containing apartments and shops. The impression is of a college or cathedral city. -- http://stationsquarestudios.com/about-forest-hills-ny/ Between 1909 and 1922, the Foundation spent nearly a sixth of its capital to build Forest Hills Gardens, a model suburban community for working families designed by architect Frederick Law Olmstead. The aim was to demonstrate the economic and social viability of an intelligently planned suburban community. -- http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russell_Sage_Foundation [work]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>American</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Tudor Revival</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Georgian Revival</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>Richard Guy Wilson Archive</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>Architecture and City Planning</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>garden suburbs</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Russell Sage Foundation</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>urban planning</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>commercial complexes</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>squares (open spaces)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>stonework</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>arches</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>kiosks</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>arch bridges</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>tunnels</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>Continental Avenue (71st Avenue), Burns Street, Greenaway Terrace, and Dartmouth Street, Forest Hills, Queens, New York, United States (neighborhood)</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:spatial>40.719444, -73.845194</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://stor.artstor.org/iiif/2014/06/11/13/41328049-3739-470e-a8c5-29be35f15f4a_deflate.tif/full/!250,250/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>https://search.lib.virginia.edu/items/i_3021588</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
