<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<?xml-model href="https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd"
      type="application/xml"
      schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<!-- Generated using uvaMAP2DPLA.xsl (v. 1.0) on 2022-12-14 at 8:15 p.m. -->
<mdRecord xmlns="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu"
          xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
          xmlns:edm="http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu https://dplava.lib.virginia.edu/dplava.xsd">
   <dcterms:provenance>University of Virginia</dcterms:provenance>
   <dcterms:type>still image</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:identifier>2833285</dcterms:identifier>
   <dcterms:title>Christ the King Parish Church, general view</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:creator>Byrne, Barry (American architect, 1892-1967) [work]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Goff, Bruce Alonzo (American architect, 1904-1982) [work]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Iannelli, Alfonso (Italian sculptor and designer, 1888-1965, active in United States) [work]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:creator>Wilson, Richard Guy [photographer]</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:publisher>Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia</dcterms:publisher>
   <dcterms:created>1988-07</dcterms:created>
   <dcterms:medium>brick (clay product) [work]</dcterms:medium>
   <dcterms:description>West Elevation</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>In 1901, oil was discovered in the Tulsa area, which attracted oilmen from the east coast, many of whom were Irish Catholic. Originally these parishioners were members of Holy Family Church led by Father Heiring. Eventually Father Heiring began petitioning Bishop Meerschaert about dividing the church due to it’s large size. In February of 1917, Father Heiring received approval to search for a location on which to found another parish. He purchased a square block which included a two-story house on the corner of Sixteenth and Rockford which had belonged to a Catholic and real estate executive, Joseph Friend, for seventeen thousand dollars and established the second parish in Tulsa. Bishop Meerschaert chose Father Charles Prosper Standaert, a Belgium native, to be the founding pastor of The Sacred Heart Parish which was formally established on July 2, 1917. Father Standaert moved in and set up a chapel in one part of the home to offer daily mass, however, parishioners continued going to Holy Family for Sunday Mass. Construction of a two-story red brick Romanesque church began within a couple of months. It included a school with six classrooms in the basement and was located next to the house which is where the parish office is today. On Sunday, March 17, 1918, Sacred Heart celebrated its first Mass. In February 1924, within six days of each other, both Bishop Meerschaert and Fr. Standaert passed away. A successor Bishop Francis Clement Kelley made his first trip to Tulsa in November 1924. With the increase of members, due again to the oil boom in Tulsa, came the need for larger church facilities. Bishop Kelley admired the work of Francis Barry Byrne, who was a former partner of Frank Lloyd Wright, and commissioned him for the project. Faced with decisions on placement of the church on the property without destroying existing facilities, and keeping in mind that Kelley had planned for the parish to be the home of the bishop, Byrne suggested adding the rectory to the back of the church, allowing the old church to be used for the school. In May 1927, less than seventeen months after Pope Pius XI created a new feast for the liturgical calendar, “Church of The Christ King” appeared on the letterhead of correspondence from Msgr. James F. McGuire, now pastor, to Bishop Kelley. This is the first evidence of the name change from Sacred Heart and it is believed that Church of Christ the King was the first church in the world to be so dedicated. Christ the King was formally dedicated three years and one day after groundbreaking on May 13, 1928. The church was designed to be wider than long and the sanctuary is triangular and positioned deep into the congregational seating. The altar is carved limestone and Emil Frei, Inc., designed the mosaic of Christ which is empanelled behind it. Tulsa architect Bruce Goff designed the mosaics at the two side altars. The stained glass windows designed by Alfonso Iannelli and produced by the Temple Art Glass Company of Chicago, depict Kings who are canonized saints on the North side and those on the South are two kings of the Old Testament and the three Magi. Each king is portrayed offering his crown in homage to Christ. In the 1920’s, Christ the King Church was considered innovative and, to some, radical. It’s design combines Gothic, Byzantine and Art Deco architecture. -- http://www.ctktulsa.org/our-parish/history/ [work]</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>American</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Art Deco</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Gothic (Medieval)</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:description>Byzantine</dcterms:description>
   <dcterms:isPartOf>Richard Guy Wilson Archive</dcterms:isPartOf>
   <dcterms:rights>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</dcterms:rights>
   <dcterms:subject>Architecture and City Planning</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Roman Catholicism</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>renovation</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>religious buildings</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>finials</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>masonry</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>brickwork (masonry)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>handrails</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>railings (balustrades)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>steps</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>cresting</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>panes (architectural elements)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>pinnacles</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>moldings (object components)</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:spatial>1520 South Rockford, Tulsa, Oklahoma, United States</dcterms:spatial>
   <dcterms:spatial>36.139690, -95.972805</dcterms:spatial>
   <edm:preview>https://stor.artstor.org/iiif/2014/04/17/12/2bf8c011-c223-4f3a-98f7-747dfefb66a6_deflate.tif/full/!250,250/0/default.jpg</edm:preview>
   <edm:isShownAt>https://search.lib.virginia.edu/items/i_2833285</edm:isShownAt>
</mdRecord>
